<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-CERTS MODULE="M-CERTS" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="done" VERSION="1.7.0">
  <test-files>
    <file>tests/certs/validate_cert_strategy.sh</file>
    <file>tests/certs/validate_cert_docs.sh</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">bash tests/certs/validate_cert_strategy.sh</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">bash tests/certs/validate_cert_docs.sh</check-2>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Apex and wildcard certificates exist at stable mount paths and are readable by the app container.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-1b kind="success">When REG.RU credentials are present, DNS-01 is completed automatically without interactive TXT entry.</scenario-1b>
    <scenario-1c kind="success">An imported certificate pair is staged into the same stable mount paths and remains readable by the app container.</scenario-1c>
    <scenario-1d kind="success">An already issued certificate pair can be exported from one VPS and imported on another without invoking a new Let’s Encrypt issuance flow.</scenario-1d>
    <scenario-2 kind="failure">DNS challenge prerequisites are missing or TXT propagation is not yet visible, and the installer keeps the operator in the guided wait loop instead of continuing blindly.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Renewal failure is visible before live traffic breaks.</scenario-3>
  </scenarios>
  <critical-invariants>
    <invariant-1>Wildcard certificate flow is explicit and not silently downgraded.</invariant-1>
    <invariant-2>Certificate material persists across container restarts.</invariant-2>
    <invariant-3>Guided manual DNS-01 does not continue until the requested TXT value is publicly visible.</invariant-3>
  </critical-invariants>
  <side-effects>
    <effect-1>Writes certificate and renewal files to host storage.</effect-1>
  </side-effects>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-CERTS][bootstrap][SELECT_CHALLENGE]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-CERTS][bootstrap][REQUEST_CERT]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-CERTS][bootstrap][PERSIST_PATHS]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-CERTS][renew][RENEW_CERT]</marker-4>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Do not log provider credentials, tokens, or private key material.</rule-1>
  </redaction-rules>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Challenge selection and path rendering checks.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Real certificate issuance on a disposable domain or staging endpoint.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>443 edge serves valid TLS for portal and proxy routing.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
</V-M-CERTS>
